Guide to the Henry R. Luce Papers 1894-2004 (bulk, 1932-1967) MS 3014
New-York Historical Society
- Series V. Subject Name Files, 1894-1995 (bulk 1933-1967); 205880; 30.1 Linear feet
  - Subseries V.B. Name Files B, 1910-1974 (bulk 1933-1967); 205886
    - Clark, Grenville, 1943-1960; 218396 (Box 114, Folder 4)
      Includes the pamphlet "Austin-Wadsworth National War Service Act" prepared by the Citizens Committee for a National War Service Act.
    - Clark, General Mark W., 1946-1957; 218398 (Box 114, Folder 5)
      Includes a draft of Clark's article "The Unhappy Truth" concerning Soviet tactics and aims.
    - Clark, Jinx Heffelfinger, 1954; 218399 (Box 114, Folder 5)
    - Clark, Richard, 1951-1959; 218400 (Box 114, Folder 5)
    - Clarke, Ashley, 1955-1956; 218401 (Box 114, Folder 5)
    - Clarke, Dana C., 1948; 218402 (Box 114, Folder 5)
    - Clay, Lucius D., 1950-1966; 218403 (Box 114, Folder 5)
    - Clayburgh, Alma, 1953; 218404 (Box 114, Folder 5)
    - Cleary, D. M., 1952-1953; 218405 (Box 114, Folder 5)
    - Clement, Governor Frank G., 1965; 218406 (Box 114, Folder 5)
    - Clements, Rex S., 1947-1960; 218408 (Box 114, Folder 5)
    - Clemow, Bice, 1945; 218409 (Box 114, Folder 5)
    - Clinchy, Everett R. (folder 1 of 2), 1938-1965; 218410 (Box 114, Folder 5)
      Includes the Constitution of The National Conference of Christians and Jews.
    - Clinchy, Everett R. (folder 2 of 2) - oversize, 1951; 218411 (Box OS-Small)
      Contains a blank copy of the charter issued by the organization World Brotherhood with attached correspondence.
    - Clurman, Shirley, 1961-1966; 218412 (Box 115, Folder 1)
    - Cobb, Irvin S. (Mr. and Mrs.), 1941-1952; 218413 (Box 115, Folder 1)
      Includes a personal unsigned letter from Cobb to Clare Boothe Luce.
    - Cochran, Lady, 1956; 218414 (Box 115, Folder 1)
    - Cochrane, Thomas, 1944; 218415 (Box 115, Folder 1)
    - Coffin, Henry Sloane, 1940-1954; 218416 (Box 115, Folder 1)
      Includes a sermon made by Reverend Coffin.
    - Cohan, George M., 1939; 218417 (Box 115, Folder 1)
    - Cohen, Dr. Sidney, 1963-1965; 218418 (Box 115, Folder 1)
    - Cole, William G., 1956; 218419 (Box 115, Folder 1)
    - Colefax, Sybil, 1938-1944; 218420 (Box 115, Folder 1)
    - Colville, John R., 1955-1961; 218421 (Box 115, Folder 1)
    - Compton, Arthur H., 1938; 218422 (Box 115, Folder 1)
    - Cone, Fairfax, 1963; 218423 (Box 115, Folder 1)
    - Constantine, King of Greece, 1964-1965; 218435 (Box 115, Folder 2)
    - Cooke, Platt, 1938-1959; 218437 (Box 115, Folder 2)
    - Coons, Arthur G., 1951-1963; 218441 (Box 115, Folder 2)
    - Cooper, Alfred Duff, 1940-1946; 218442 (Box 115, Folder 2)
    - Cooper, John Sherman, 1955; 218443 (Box 115, Folder 2)
    - Cord, Mrs. E. L. (Virginia), 1965; 218444 (Box 115, Folder 2)
    - Cordier, Andrew, 1954; 218445 (Box 115, Folder 2)
    - Cornell, Paul L., 1940; 218446 (Box 115, Folder 2)
      Includes a testimonial by Charles and Mary Beard for Cornell's candidacy for the Senate.
    - Cortney, Philip, 1959-1962; 218449 (Box 115, Folder 2)
      Includes copies of correspondence from John M. Leddy, Jacques Rueff, and Masamichi Yamagiwa regarding monetary stability.
    - Cotten, Joseph, 1959; 218450 (Box 115, Folder 2)
    - Cousins, Norman, 1941-1966; 218461 (Box 115, Folder 2)
      Consists of copies.
    - Couturier, Father, 1950; 218462 (Box 115, Folder 2)
    - Coward, Noel, 1940; 218463 (Box 115, Folder 2)
    - Coward, Thomas, 1953; 218464 (Box 115, Folder 2)
    - Cowles, Gardner (Mr. and Mrs.), 1938-1961; 218467 (Box 115, Folder 3)
      Includes the speech "A Report on Our Propaganda and Information Services in Asia" by Fleur Cowles.
    - Cowles, John (Mr. and Mrs.), 1937-1965; 218468 (Box 115, Folder 3)
      Includes the pamphlets "Britain Under Fire: Impressions of War Time England in January and February, 1941" and "Report on Europe."
    - Cowles, Virginia, 1939; 218469 (Box 115, Folder 3)
    - Cowley, W. H., 1943; 218470 (Box 115, Folder 3)
    - Cox, Wallace, 1935-1944; 218472 (Box 115, Folder 3)
    - Coze, Paul, 1961-1962; 218474 (Box 115, Folder 3)
    - Crane, Charles E., 1936; 218475 (Box 115, Folder 3)
    - Crane, Charles R., 1936; 218477 (Box 115, Folder 3)
      Includes a blank postcard with the image of sand hills near Palm Springs, California.
    - Crane, F. A., 1953; 218478 (Box 115, Folder 3)
    - Cravath, Paul D., 1936-1952; 218479 (Box 115, Folder 4)
    - Crawford, R. F., 1937; 218480 (Box 115, Folder 4)
    - Cretella, Albert W., 1953; 218481 (Box 115, Folder 4)
    - Cripps, Stafford, 1945; 218482 (Box 115, Folder 4)
    - Critchley, A. C., 1944; 218483 (Box 115, Folder 4)
    - Crocker, Stuart, 1937-1953; 218487 (Box 115, Folder 4)
      Includes the results of a poll taken at Crocker's annual party (26 April 1939) on the topic of politics and economy.
    - Cromwell, James H. R., 1936-1939; 218488 (Box 115, Folder 4)
    - Cronin, A. J., 1941; 218489 (Box 115, Folder 4)
    - Crosby, Jr. John, 1936-1948; 218493 (Box 115, Folder 4)
    - Crosley, John, 1935; 218494 (Box 115, Folder 4)
    - Crosley, Jr. Powell, 1939; 218496 (Box 115, Folder 4)
    - Cross, Wilbur L., 1937; 218497 (Box 115, Folder 4)
    - Crowe, Earl, 1947; 218500 (Box 115, Folder 4)
    - Crowe, Philip K., 1938-1964; 218501 (Box 115, Folder 4)
    - Crowninshield, Frank, 1947; 218502 (Box 115, Folder 4)
    - Crum, Bartley C., 1942-1959; 218504 (Box 115, Folder 4)
      Includes the "Salt Lake Charter" memorandum stating the platform and principles of the members of the Republican National Committee from eleven western states.
    - Cudahy, Mrs. E. A., 1966; 218535 (Box 115, Folder 5)
    - Cudlipp, Chandler, 1949; 218536 (Box 115, Folder 5)
    - Culbertson, Ely, 1941-1944; 218537 (Box 115, Folder 5)
      Includes the pamphlet "A System to Win This War and to Win the Peace to Come: The World Federation Plan" by Culbertson.
    - Culbertson, William S., 1955; 218538 (Box 115, Folder 5)
    - Cullen, Thomas S., 1947; 218539 (Box 115, Folder 5)
    - Cuneo, John F., 1945-1967; 218540 (Box 115, Folder 5)
    - Currie, Laughlin, 1941-1942; 218541 (Box 115, Folder 5)
    - Curtice, Harlow, 1954; 218542 (Box 115, Folder 5)
    - Cutting, Suydam, 1936-1961; 218543 (Box 115, Folder 5)
    - Dabcevich, Egon, 1953-1954; 218544 (Box 116, Folder 1)
    - Dalton, Hugh, 1945; 218545 (Box 116, Folder 1)
    - Damon, R. S., 1952; 218546 (Box 116, Folder 1)
    - Danaher, John A., 1938-1944; 218547 (Box 116, Folder 1)
    - Danforth, William H., 1945; 218548 (Box 116, Folder 1)
    - Darling, Arthur B., 1941; 218549 (Box 116, Folder 1)
    - Davenport, John, 1947-1967; 218550 (Box 116, Folder 1)
      Includes a letter regarding the Vietnam War.
    - Davenport, Mrs. Russell, 1937-1955; 218551 (Box 116, Folder 1)
    - David, Donald K., 1943-1950; 218552 (Box 116, Folder 1)
    - Davidson, Jo, 1940-1969; 218553 (Box 116, Folder 1)
      Includes a photograph of a bust of HRL done by Jo Davidson.
    - Davies, A. Powell, 1942; 218554 (Box 116, Folder 1)
    - Davies, Joseph E., 1937-1953; 218555 (Box 116, Folder 1)
    - Davis, Mrs. Bronson H., 1935; 218556 (Box 116, Folder 2)
    - Davis, Mrs. Loyal, 1965-1966; 218557 (Box 116, Folder 2)
      Includes Ronald Reagan's speech "A Plan for Action."
    - Davison, F. Trubee, 1937-1962; 218558 (Box 116, Folder 2)
    - Davison, Henry P., 1935-1965; 218559 (Box 116, Folder 2)
      Includes a photograph of Davison.
    - Davison, R. F., 1949-1950; 218560 (Box 116, Folder 2)
    - Day, George Parmly, 1936-1941; 218561 (Box 116, Folder 2)
    - Day, Joseph P., 1940-1944; 218562 (Box 116, Folder 2)
    - Deak, Francis, 1956-1962; 218563 (Box 116, Folder 3)
    - Dealey, Ted, 1946-1951; 218564 (Box 116, Folder 3)
    - Dearborn, Ned H., 1938; 218565 (Box 116, Folder 3)
    - Dearing, Albin, 1948; 218566 (Box 116, Folder 3)
    - De Bekessy, Mrs. Eleanor, 1943-1957; 218567 (Box 116, Folder 3)
      Includes a carbon copy of an invitation form letter to a dinner in honor of President Ngo Dinh Diem of Vietnam.
    - De Benouville, General, 1948; 218568 (Box 116, Folder 3)
    - De Bruine, Dr. N. A. C. Slotemaker, 1945; 218569 (Box 116, Folder 3)
    - De Chambrun, Rene, 1938-1949; 218570 (Box 116, Folder 3)
      Includes a handwritten letter dated 28 September 1939 sent from the French battle front.
    - De Forceville, Philip, 1935; 218571 (Box 116, Folder 3)
    - De Gaulle, Charles, 1949; 218572 (Box 116, Folder 3)
      Contains a copy of a "very hasty and incomplete notes on private conversation with General de Gaulle" and an original thank you note from de Gaulle.
    - De Lattre, Marechal J. de Tassigny, 1949-1952; 218573 (Box 116, Folder 3)
    - De Montgomery, Madeleine, 1946; 218574 (Box 116, Folder 3)
    - Dempsey, John B., 1938; 218575 (Box 116, Folder 3)
    - Dennis, W. H., 1951-1952; 218576 (Box 116, Folder 3)
    - Depinet, Ned, 1947; 218577 (Box 116, Folder 3)
    - De Rethy, Marie-Liliane, 1959; 218578 (Box 116, Folder 3)
    - Derlanger, Leo, 1956; 218579 (Box 116, Folder 3)
    - De Rothschild, Baron Philipe, 1960-1965; 218580 (Box 116, Folder 3)
    - Desai, Morarji, 1961-1962; 218581 (Box 116, Folder 3)
    - Devane, William Carr, 1939-1965; 218582 (Box 116, Folder 4)
    - Devereux, Fred L., 1936; 218583 (Box 116, Folder 4)
      Includes the article "I See A Plant Grow" by Dr. Glenn Frank.
    - Dewey, Thomas E., 1937-1958; 218584 (Box 116, Folder 4)
      Correspondence from Dewey consists of copies.
    - Dickey, Charles D., 1960; 218585 (Box 116, Folder 4)
    - Dickson, Professor Harold E., 1955; 218586 (Box 116, Folder 4)
    - Diem, Ngo Dinh, 1957; 218587 (Box 116, Folder 4)
      Includes guest list, biographies, schedule, and memoranda dealing with the logistics of the dinner in honor of Diem. Correspondents include David Sarnoff, William V. Griffin, Leo Cherne, William P. Hunt, and Tran Van Chuong.
    - Dillingham, Mrs. Walter, 1963; 218588 (Box 116, Folder 4)
    - Dillon, Clarence, 1952-1956; 218589 (Box 116, Folder 4)
    - Dillon, Douglas, 1956-1965; 218590 (Box 116, Folder 4)
    - Dingle, David, 1965; 218591 (Box 116, Folder 4)
    - Dirksen, Everett McKinley, 1966; 218592 (Box 116, Folder 4)
    - Disney, Walt, 1943; 218593 (Box 116, Folder 5)
    - Dixon, Sir Pierson, 1959-1961; 218594 (Box 116, Folder 5)
    - Dobrynin, Anatoly, 1962; 218595 (Box 116, Folder 5)
    - Dodge, Washington, 1962; 218596 (Box 116, Folder 5)
    - DonDero, Gertrude, 1955; 218597 (Box 116, Folder 5)
    - Donnelley, Gaylord and Thomas, 1945-1967; 218598 (Box 116, Folder 5)
    - Donner, Frederick G., 1963; 218599 (Box 116, Folder 5)
    - Donovan, William J., 1941; 218600 (Box 116, Folder 5)
    - Douglas, James H., 1940; 218601 (Box 116, Folder 5)
    - Douglas, Lewis W., 1940-1966; 218602 (Box 116, Folder 5)
      Includes a telegram with the text of a confidential letter intended for President Roosevelt.
    - Douglas, Lloyd, 1943; 218605 (Box 116, Folder 5)
    - Douglas, William O., 1942-1965; 218692 (Box 117, Folder 1)
    - Dowling, Eddie, 1951-1961; 218693 (Box 117, Folder 1)
    - Doyle, Walter, 1953; 218694 (Box 117, Folder 1)
      Contains a memo from Doyle to the Ambassador (Clare Boothe Luce?) regarding the picture stories about her in Giorno and Le Oro.
    - Drake, Carlos, 1935-1941; 218695 (Box 117, Folder 1)
      Includes an issue of the newspaper The Carmel Pine Cone.
    - Dreyfuss, Henry, 1937-1966; 218697 (Box 117, Folder 1)
      Includes a pamphlet with the speech "Reveal the Subject and Conceal the Art (or the Twenty-First Century Junk Dealer's Best Friend)" given by Dreyfuss at the 15th International Design Conference.
    - Drewey, John E., 1955; 218698 (Box 117, Folder 1)
    - Driscoll, Egbert G., 1947; 218699 (Box 117, Folder 1)
    - Driscoll, Elizabeth, 1955; 218700 (Box 117, Folder 1)
    - Drucker, Peter F., 1949; 218701 (Box 117, Folder 1)
    - Dulles, John Foster - Law, 1957-1959; 218702 (Box 117, Folder 2)
      Includes drafts of notes describing the talk with Dulles at the Department of State on 22 August 1957.
    - Dulles, John Foster - Oral History Project (folder 1 of 2), 1953-1966; 218703 (Box 117, Folder 2)
      Includes a transcript of an interview with HRL for the Princeton University oral history, and a personal memorandum describing the meeting with Dulles on 7 January 1953.
    - Dulles, John Foster - Oral History Project (folder 2 of 2)[Restricted], 1964 July 28; 218724 (Offsite-box RC18, Folder 7)
      Contains a reel tape of the interview.
    - Dulles, John Foster - Speeches and Articles, 1943-1959; 218738 (Box 117, Folder 3)
      Includes the speeches "The United Nations - Its Challenge to America," "Freedom Through Sacrifice," "World Brotherhood Through the State," "Foreign Policy - Ideals, Not Deals," "The Defense of Freedom," "Evolution or Revolution," and "Peace Through Law." In addition there is a draft of an untitled speech to be made at the Cathedral of St. John the Divine on 28 October 1943, and a portion of an address on the Dumbarton Oaks Proposal.
    - Dulles, John Foster - Miscellaneous (folder 1 of 2), 1939-1951; 218739 (Box 117, Folder 4)
      Includes a typescript copy of a letter from Dulles to Madame Chiang Kai-shek, a long excerpt from an untitled speech made before the Cleveland Council on World Affairs, and typed notes from HRL regarding Christian colleges in China.
    - Dulles, John Foster - Miscellaneous (folder 2 of 2), 1952-1961; 218740 (Box 117, Folder 4)
      Includes memoranda describing HRL's meetings with Dulles, and a program for "A Service of Christian Witness in Remembrance of The Honorable John Foster Dulles."
    - Drummond, Roscoe, 1956; 218741 (Box 117, Folder 4)
    - Duke, Angier Biddle, 1961; 218742 (Box 117, Folder 4)
    - Duffy, E. J., 1952; 218743 (Box 117, Folder 4)
    - Dulles, Allen W., 1950-1957; 218744 (Box 117, Folder 4)
    - Dun, Bishop Angus, 1957; 218745 (Box 117, Folder 4)
      Includes a sermon made in the Washington Cathedral.
    - Dunbaugh, George J., 1935; 218746 (Box 117, Folder 4)
    - Duncan, R. F., 1941; 218747 (Box 117, Folder 4)
      Includes a memorandum dealing with the chairmen of United China Relief in various cities.
    - Dunn, Arthur, 1938-1942; 218748 (Box 117, Folder 5)
      Includes the pamphlet "Thirty Million Jobs."
    - Dunne, Irene, 1948-1951; 218749 (Box 117, Folder 5)
    - Dupuy, Pierre, 1953; 218750 (Box 117, Folder 5)
    - Durant, John, 1938; 218751 (Box 117, Folder 5)
    - Durbrow, Elbridge, 1954-1961; 218752 (Box 117, Folder 5)
    - Earle, Governor George, 1938; 218753 (Box 117, Folder 5)
    - Eban, Abba, 1959; 218754 (Box 117, Folder 5)
    - Eberstadt, Ferdinand, 1938-1962; 218759 (Box 117, Folder 6)
      Includes memoranda analysing the 1944 election campaign and the subject of war, and Volume I of the Report to the Honorable James Forrestal Secretary of the Navy on Unification of the War and Navy Departments and Post-War Organization for National Security.
    - Ebtehaj, A. H., 1952-1965; 218761 (Box 118, Folder 1)
    - Eddy, Sherwood, 1937-1954; 218764 (Box 118, Folder 1)
      Includes brochures and brochure proofs for "The American Seminar" and "The European Seminar," and a draft of "A Four-fold Plan for India."
    - Eden, Sir Anthony, 1940-1956; 218765 (Box 118, Folder 1)
    - Edison, Governor Charles, 1943-1961; 218768 (Box 118, Folder 1)
      Includes minutes of the meeting of the Executive Committee of the Board of Directors of the National War Fund, Inc.
    - Edmonds, Harry, 1953; 218770 (Box 118, Folder 1)
    - Eichelberger, General Robert, 1946; 218774 (Box 118, Folder 1)
    - Eiges, Sydney T., 1955; 218776 (Box 118, Folder 2)
      Includes a National Broadcasting Company (NBC) studio pass card for 1956.
    - Einaudi, Luigi, 1955; 218777 (Box 118, Folder 2)
    - Eisenhower, Dwight D. - Far East, 1952-1965; 218782 (Box 118, Folder 2)
      Includes memoranda titled "The Vital Interests of the USA in Asia," "Outline of Strategy for Asia," "A Republican Policy for Asia" as well as others dealing with policy in the Pacific. In addition there is a petition addressed to the President expressing opposition to the admission of the Chinese People's Republic to the United Nations. Correspondents include Charles R. Hook, and Eisenhower (copies).
    - Eisenhower, Dwight D. - Birthday Dinner, 14 October 1965, 218785 (Box 118, Folder 2)
      Includes lists of names.
    - Eisenhower, Dwight D. - Law, 1958; 218787 (Box 118, Folder 2)
      Includes a carbon copy of the text of the President's letter to Arthur Larson regarding the establishment of the Rule of Law Center at Duke University.
    - Eisenhower, Dwight D. - National Presbyterian Church, 1957-1961; 218789 (Box 118, Folder 2)
      Includes copies of correspondence regarding the fundraising efforts for the construction of the church, and a copy of a signed statement from Eisenhower for a brochure about the project.
    - Eisenhower, Dwight D. - Miscellaneous (folder 1 of 2), 1950-1952; 218790 (Box 118, Folder 3)
      Includes the pamphlet "The American Assembly," a copy of a letter from Eisenhower regarding the Engineering Center at Columbia University, correspondence and memoranda dealing with the 1952 presidential campaign, and two drafts of Eisenhower's? speeches. Also includes one original letter signed by Eisenhower.
    - Eisenhower, Dwight D. - Miscellaneous (folder 2 of 2), 1953-1965; 218828 (Box 118, Folder 4)
      Includes a list of Eisenhower's appointments to the new administration, HRL's schedule for the presidential inauguration ceremonies, text of Eisenhower's foreign policy address, the pamphlet "Eisenhower's America: Notes on a Journey by a Special Correspondent of The Times," and a list of achievements of the Eisenhower presidency. Also includes an original signed letter from Eisenhower to John Cridel, and two signed letters from Mamie Eisenhower.
    - Eisenhower, Milton S., 1953-1957; 218842 (Box 118, Folder 5)
      Includes a tentative statement of objectives of the American-Korean Foundation, and the speech "Ideas at War: The Moral Conflict of Our Time."
    - Eliot, George F., 1940-1942; 218849 (Box 118, Folder 5)
    - Elizabeth II, Queen of England - 21 October 1957 Visit to New York, 218864 (Box 118, Folder 5)
      Includes two souvenir programs from the luncheon given by Robert F. Wagner at the Waldorf Astoria in honor of Queen Elizabeth II and Prince Philip.
    - El-Kateb, H. E. Hassan, 1956; 218869 (Box 118, Folder 6)
    - Ellis, Hugh, 1942; 218871 (Box 118, Folder 6)
    - Elterich, Harold N., 1942-1948; 218872 (Box 118, Folder 6)
    - Emeny, Brooks, 1941-1952; 218875 (Box 118, Folder 6)
      Includes carbon copies of letters sent by Emeny to General Frank R. McCoy and Nelson A. Rockefeller, and brochures for the Newton D. Baker Lecture Fund.
    - Emmet, Jr. Christopher T., 1944; 218878 (Box 118, Folder 6)
      Includes a speech by Emily Hahn made at a United China Relief rally in Bridgeport, CT.
    - Engel, A. Ferdinand, 1956; 218879 (Box 118, Folder 6)
    - Engel, Samuel R., 1948; 218880 (Box 118, Folder 6)
      Includes a letter from Mrs. Lecomte du Nouy.
    - Engle, Paul, 1956-1959; 218881 (Box 118, Folder 6)
    - Enriques, Giovanni, 1954-1955; 218884 (Box 118, Folder 6)
    - Erhard, Ludwig, 1954-1966; 218887 (Box 118, Folder 6)
      Includes a prospectus for a monthly publication review titled "Focus: An International Forum for Economic Policy."
    - Ernst, Morris L., 1939-1965; 218888 (Box 119, Folder 1)
    - Espy, R. H., 1946; 218889 (Box 119, Folder 1)
    - Eurich, Alvin R., 1948; 218892 (Box 119, Folder 1)
    - Eugenides, Eugene, 1953; 218893 (Box 119, Folder 1)
    - Evans, Arthur, 1935; 218894 (Box 119, Folder 1)
    - Everitt, Sam, 1938-1951; 218901 (Box 119, Folder 1)
      Includes photographs of an unidentified road, and correspondence and memoranda on the proposed creation of The History Book Club.
    - Everett, Tom (John T.), 1951-1953; 218902 (Box 119, Folder 1)
    - Ewald, Henry T., 1937-1953; 218903 (Box 119, Folder 1)
    - Exman, Eugene, 1946-1963; 218904 (Box 119, Folder 1)
    - Faina, Count Carlo, 1953-1960; 218906 (Box 119, Folder 2)
    - Fairbank, Mrs. Kellogg, 1935; 218907 (Box 119, Folder 2)
    - Fairbanks, Jr. Douglas, 1951; 218908 (Box 119, Folder 2)
      Correspondence from Fairbanks consists of copies.
    - Fang, General Chen-Wu, 1936; 218909 (Box 119, Folder 2)
    - Faries, McIntyre, 1947-1960; 218910 (Box 119, Folder 2)
    - Farley, James, 1940-1955; 218913 (Box 119, Folder 2)
    - Farrar, John, 1938-1952; 218917 (Box 119, Folder 2)
      Includes printed materials from The League of American Writers announcing the sale of manuscripts and letters for the benefit of the Medical Bureau of the North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy, and broadsides of the newspaper column "It Makes Sense" distributed by the Committee to Defend America.
    - Fearn, Dr. Anne W., 1938; 218919 (Box 119, Folder 2)
    - Felici, Alfonso, 1956; 218920 (Box 119, Folder 2)
    - Fenn, William P., 1964; 218921 (Box 119, Folder 2)
    - Ferguson, Harold S., 1943; 218922 (Box 119, Folder 2)
    - Ferguson, Homer, 1952-1954; 218923 (Box 119, Folder 2)
    - Ferragamo, Salvatore, 1955; 218924 (Box 119, Folder 2)
    - Fey, Harold E., 1946; 218925 (Box 119, Folder 3)
    - Field, Sr. and Jr. Marshall, 1941-1964; 218926 (Box 119, Folder 3)
      Includes a draft of Field Jr.'s speech "Mass Media and Better Human Understanding."
    - Field, Robert M., 1942-1948; 218927 (Box 119, Folder 3)
      Includes a chart showing monthly disposals for the War Assets Administration.
    - Fielding, Temple, 1963; 218928 (Box 119, Folder 3)
      Includes a Danish clipping announcing HRL's appointment by the King of Denmark to be the Commander of Dannebrog.
    - Fifield, James W., 1948-1959; 218929 (Box 119, Folder 3)
      Includes a pamphlet with the sermon "Don't Manufacture Your Own Happiness" by Norman Vincent Peale.
    - Finch, E. C. K. (Kip), 1951-1955; 218930 (Box 119, Folder 3)
    - Findley, Paul, 1965; 218931 (Box 119, Folder 3)
    - Finkelstein, Louis, 1940-1963; 218932 (Box 119, Folder 4)
      Includes a preliminary announcement and invitation to the Conference on Science, Philosophy and Religion in Their Relation to the Democratic Way of Life, and memoranda regarding the Institute for Religious and Social Studies.
    - Finletter, Thomas K., 1941; 218933 (Box 119, Folder 5)
    - Firesone, Harvey, 1938-1948; 218934 (Box 119, Folder 5)
    - Fisher, Samuel H., 1944; 218935 (Box 119, Folder 5)
    - Fisher, Thomas Hart, 1937-1938; 218936 (Box 119, Folder 5)
      Includes the book State House Versus Pent House: Legal Problems of the Rhode Island Race-Track Row by Zechariah Chafee, Jr.
    - Fitch, Hugh R., 1945-1955; 218937 (Box 119, Folder 5)
      Includes the poems "Christmas Ode to the United Nations" and "The Nativity" by Fitch.
    - Fitzpatrick, Teresa S., 1943; 218938 (Box 119, Folder 6)
    - Flanders, Ralph E., 1943-1947; 218939 (Box 119, Folder 6)
      Includes a reprint of Flanders's article "Let's Face It."
    - Flemming, Arthur S., 1953; 218940 (Box 119, Folder 6)
    - Fletcher, Harris, 1945; 218941 (Box 119, Folder 6)
    - Fly, James L., 1943-1945; 218942 (Box 119, Folder 6)
      Includes a pamphlet with the address of Enders M. Voorhees before the Controllers' Institute of America.
    - Folsom, Frank, 1954-1958; 218943 (Box 119, Folder 6)
    - Fon, Antonio, 1953; 218945 (Box 119, Folder 6)
    - Forbes, Malcolm, 1957; 218946 (Box 119, Folder 6)
    - Ford, Henry and Henry Ford II, 1943-1967; 218947 (Box 119, Folder 6)
    - Ford, Lauren, 1947; 218948 (Box 120, Folder 1)
    - Forkner, Dr. C. E., 1942; 218949 (Box 120, Folder 1)
    - Fornacca, J. J., 1954; 218950 (Box 120, Folder 1)
    - Forrestal, James, 1942-1953; 218951 (Box 120, Folder 1)